Guide to the Ingram Olkin papers SC1221
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Ingram Olkin papers
1875-2014
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Olkin, Ingram
SC1221
46 Linear Feet (32 boxes)
Biographical / Historical
Ingram Olkin is best known for developing statistical analyses for evaluating policies, particularly in education. Throughout his career, Olkin conducted highly significant research concerning new and innovative statistical models and methods for the behavioral medical, and social sciences, often simultaneously. Particularly outstanding is his research into combining, statistically, the scientific results from independent studies.
Born in Waterbury, Conn., on July 23, 1924, he was the only child of Julius and Karola (nee Bander) Olkin, both immigrants from Eastern Europe. At the age of 10, Ingram and his parents moved to New York City, and he later attended DeWitt Clinton High School in the Bronx from which he graduated in 1941. He enrolled at City College of New York (CCNY), but his studies were interrupted in 1943 when he volunteered and served in the U.S. Army Air Force as a meteorologist until 1946.
Returning to CCNY, he completed his degree in mathematics and went on to obtain a master’s degree in mathematical statistics at Columbia University followed by a PhD in mathematical statistics at the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, conferred in 1951.
For his first academic position, Ingram joined the Mathematics Department faculty at Michigan State University as an assistant professor and rose through the ranks to become a full professor. During the nine years he spent at Michigan State, he enjoyed productive sabbatical leaves at the University of Chicago (1955) and Stanford (1958). In 1960 he joined the faculty of the University of Minnesota to chair the formation of a new Statistics Department. One year later, he moved permanently to Stanford University, where he held a joint appointment with the Department of Statistics and the Graduate School of Education.
Olkin’s research, teaching and other professional activities have had far-reaching influence in mathematical and educational statistics and their applications.
His scientific legacies lie in several fields, most notably multivariate statistical analysis, inequalities (especially majorization), linear algebra, and a subject called meta-analysis in which he was particularly active in his later years.
The latter subject enables researchers to combine separate studies in a manner that makes them more meaningful. Among the many books Ingram Olkin has co-authored and co-edited are Inequalities: Theory of Majorization and its Applications (with Albert Marshall) and Statistical Methods for Meta-Analysis (with Larry V. Hedges).
Ingram’s dedication to his profession was outstanding. He belonged to the editorial boards of numerous journals on statistics and other fields. While serving as its editor, Ingram successfully advocated splitting the prestigious journal Annals of Mathematical Statistics into two journals: Annals of Statistics and Annals of Probability. He was instrumental in the formation of the Journal of Educational Statistics (now called the Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics). He served as chair of the Statistics Department at Stanford (1973 –1976). He was president of the Institute of Mathematical Statistics and chair, co-chair, or member of countless committees and panels at the national level.
Olkin’s outstanding record of accomplishment and service brought him international recognition and a long list of honors and awards. Among them are the Wilks Medal and Founders Award from the American Statistical Association, a Guggenheim Fellowship, an honorary doctor of science from De Montfort University, election to the National Academy of Education, and the Melvin Zelen Leadership Award from the Department of Biostatistics at Harvard University’s School of Public Health.
Olkin also devoted considerable time and energy to increasing the number and status of women in graduate studies and in tenure-line academic positions at the university level. He was instrumental in convincing the National Science Foundation to support a successful program that brought untenured female professors of statistics to Stanford for the summer, where they could interact with some of the leading figures in the field. To the end, Ingram continued to be an advocate for giving women and minorities opportunities and fair treatment in all respects. In recognition of his support for women in statistics, he became the first (and only) male recipient of the Elizabeth L. Scott Award from the Committee of Presidents of Statistical Societies.
Ingram was a member of the Stanford Emeriti Council, a group that plans quarterly talks by distinguished retirees for emeritus faculty and staff and their spouses. He was also a member of a group that planned a series of presentations on successful aging for such an audience.
Ingram was an active participant in monthly faculty lunches at Stanford’s Hillel.
He loved theater, art, classical music and especially opera, much of which he attended in San Francisco or elsewhere in his worldwide travels.
Ingram was survived by his wife Anita; his daughter Vivian, her husband Sim Sitkin, their children Leah and Jared; his daughter Rhoda and children Noah and Sophia; and his daughter Julia and children Rachel and Jeremy.
RICHARD COTTLE AND JULIA OLKIN
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Mathematical statistics.; Statistics -- Study and teaching.; Olkin, Ingram
- Papers
  - Tong-Olkin - "Peakedness in Multivariate Distributions", 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Olkin/Tomsky - "A New Class of Multivariate Tests Based on the Union-..", undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Guttman-Olkin - Modeling Interlaboratory Differences, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Guttman-Olkin - Retention or Attrition Models, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Hu/Olkin - A Numerical Procedure for Finding..., 1990 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - NSF Proposal Forms (1/2), 1982-1991 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - NSF Proposal Forms (2/2), 1979-1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - NSF Proposal - Quantitative Synthesis, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - NSF - Original, 1978-1981 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - NSF - Proposal, 1972-1976 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - NSF - Renewal and Supplements - Multi-Dimensional..., 1991 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Marshall-Olkin - Functional Equations for Multivariate Exponential Distributions, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Marshall-Olkin - Multivariate Distribution Generated from Mixtures, 12/1/1986 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Marsaglia/Olkin - Generation of Correlation Matrices, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Marsaglia/Olkin - Generation of Correlation Matrices, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Marshall-Olkin, 3/1/1980 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Some problems to consider - AWM - IO, 7/1/1981 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Marshall/Olkin - Families of Multivariate Distribution, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Petkau, Zidek - Olkin, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Nanda/Olkin "Theoretical Aspects of Component...", undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Nanda/Olkin "Factor Analytic Techniques for Interbattery Comparisons", undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Nanda-Olkin Structural Prop. of Interbattery, 1989, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Yitzhaki and Olkin - "Concentration Curves", 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - S. Yitzhaki and I. Olkin - Concentration Curves, 1989-1991 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Yitzhaki and Olkin - Gini Regression Analysis, 1987-1991 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Marshall and Olkin - "A Family of Bivariate Distributions", 3/1/1984 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Hedges and Olkin - "Clustering Estimates of Effect Magnitude", 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Hedges and Olkin - "Joint Distributions of Some Indices", 1983 Aug (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Marshall and Olkin - "Majorization and Schur Convexity:...", undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Marshall and Olkin - Multivariate Exponential Distributions, 1982 June (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Marshall and Olkin "Jensen's Inequality Implies Hadamard's Inequality", 1980-1980 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Marshall/Olkin - "A Family of Bivariate Distributions Generated by the Bivariate", 1983-1985 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Hedges/Olkin - Nonparametric Estimators of Effect Size in Meta-Analysis, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - NSF - Domains of Attraction of Multivariate Extreme Value Distributions - AWM & IO, c. 1981 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Marshall/Olkin "Inequalities for the Trace Equation", 1985 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Marshall-Olkin Trace Function, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Marshall-IO Volume - A bivariate Uniform Distribution, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Marshall-Olkin - Bivariate Distribution, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Marshall-Olkin - Errata for Inequalities, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Marshall-Olkin - Matrix Versions of the Cauchy and.., 1990 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Marshall-Olkin - Bivariate Distribution Gen. from Polya-Eggenberger Urn Mod., 1990 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Kadane,Olkin,Scarsini - "Inequalities for Predictive Ratios, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Original Draft - Kendall/Olkin, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Statistical Modeling and Decision Science / Lieberman and Olkin, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Luzar/Olkin - Comparison of Simulation Methods..., 1990 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Marshall & Olkin - "Multivariate Exponential and Geometric Distributions w/ Limited Memory, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Marshall/Olkin - "Inequalities for the trace", 1983 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Hedges/Olkin - Regression Models in Research Synthesis, 1982 July (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Hedges/Olkin "Joint Distribution..Based on Correlation Coefficients", 1983 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Hedges/Olkin - Meta Analysis: A New View and a Preview, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Hedges/Olkin - Estimation of the parameters of some noncentral distributions, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - AWM/IO - Geometric Minima and Maxima II, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - AWM/IO A Doubly Stochastic Matrix Closest to a Given Matrix, 1981 July (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - AWM/IO - Inequalities Via Majorization --An Introduction, 1981 Sept (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Marshall-Olkin "Inequalities via Majorization", undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - AWM/IO Multivariate New Better than Used Distr., 1979 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Marshall/Olkin - "Multivariate Exponential Distribution", 1983 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Marshall/Ghurye - "Shock Processes with Aftereffects and Multivariate Lack..", 1982 Oct (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Marshall-Olkin/Oberwolfach, undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Marshall-Olkin Introduction, undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Hedges-Olkin - Final Report, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Hedges/Olkin - Chapter E, undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence re Publications, 1981-1989 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Stanford University Operating Budget, 1975 Oct (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Educ 250C, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Educ 351A, 1978-1981 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - National Science Foundation Proposals, 1982 March 17 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - The Institute for Professional Education, 1978 May 1-5 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Shrikhande/Olkin-An Extension of Wilks' Test for the Equality of Means, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Olkin/DAS Gupta/Eaton/Periman/Sobel - Inequalities on the Probability Content of Convex Regions for Elliptically..., 1971 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Letter to Mathematical Reviews Associate Executive Editor Jane Kister, 1992 Oct. 14 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Doctoral Students in Math Methods Program, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Various Letters, 1976-1990 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Identically Distributed Linear Forms and the Normal Distribution, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Library Project, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Letters to and from Other Professors, 1983-1991 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Current Papers, 1989 Sept. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Notes, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Generation of Random Orthogonal Matrices, 1985 April 10 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Gallery, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Committee on the Status of Graduate Women, 1982 Nov. 12 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Bivariate Distribution, 1985 April (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Wilks Committee, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Lecture I, 1982 April 21 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Distribution Theory, Undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Letter to Lori Thombs, 1991 Nov. 15 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - On Fitting Multivariate Extreme Value Distributions, with Applications to Environmental Data, 1989 Dec. (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Notes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Estimating a Constant of Proportionality for Exchangeable Random Variables, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - An Extremal Problem for Positive Definite Matrices, Letters, Notes, NSF Reviews, Statistical Inference for Constants of Proportionality, 1976-1983 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - NSF Proposal-Mathematical Methods in Educational Research, 1975-1977 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - NSF Review - Math Sciences Board, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - NSF #840, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Mathematical Review, Notes, 1995 COPSS Awards Presentation Pamphlets, 1980-1995 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Inequalities of the Probability Content of Convex Regions for Elliptically Contoured Distributions, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Regular Confidence Regions for the Means of Multivariate Normal Distributions, II, 1967 Jan. (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - On Multivariate Normal Probabilities of Rectangles: their Dependence on Correlations, 1967 Jan. (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Four Methods of Constructing Confidence Intervals for the Means of Multivariate Normal Distributions, 1966 Aug. (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Letters and Notes, circa 1968 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Proposal to the National Science Foundation, 1984 Jan. 5 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Statistical Sciences Grant Selection Committee, 1987 Jan 13 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Letters to Other Professors, 1985-1991 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Proposal for Partial Support of the International Conference on Foundations of Statistical Inference, 1985 Dec. 15-18 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Annual Faculty Report, 1967-1984 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Letters about Committee on The-Information-On-Statistics-Programs Brochure, Inequalities, Lectures, 1981-1985 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Israel Conference, 1985 Dec. (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Linear Algebra and Statistics Preface, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - World Fertility Survey, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Law Brochure, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Committee on Research, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Characterization Problems in Mathematical Statistics, undated (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Class Notes, 1980 April (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Letter to E.F. Beckenbach, 1981 Jan. 22 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - CUAFA, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Criminal Justice, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Bivariate Distribution, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - NSF Report: "Statistics: Change and Resources in a Growing Science", 1981 Dec. 1 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Maximum Likelihood Estimation in a Two-Way Analysis of Variance with Correlated Errors in One Classification, 1980 Jan. (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - NSF Correspondence, 1976-1979 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - MULT Courses 324A, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Berkeley-Stanford Symposium Folder I, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Multivariate Class Notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Estimation and Testing Problems in a Wishart Distribution Chapter I, undated (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Chapter II Rotations and Preliminaries, undated (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Chapter III, undated (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Chapter IV The Cramer Rao Bound for the Variance of Estimates if Sigma and an Inequality in Gamma Functions Using this Bound, undated (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Chapter V A Multivariate Correlation Model with Mixed Discrete and Continuous Variables, undated (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Chapter IV Some Testing Problems Concerning the Comparison of Dispersion Matrices (In Multivariate Normal Distribution) when There is Intra Class Correlation, undated (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Chapter II Rotations and Preliminaries, undated (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Chapter IV The Cramer Rao Bound for the Variance of Estimates if Sigma and an Inequality in Gamma Functions Using this Bound, undated (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Chapter III, undated (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Chapter IV The Cramer Rao Bound for the Variance of Estimates if Sigma and an Inequality in Gamma Functions Using this Bound, undated (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Remarks on a Matrix Theorem Arising in Statistics, undated (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Chapter 2 The Use of Regression Analysis, undated (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Estimation and Testing Problems in a Wishart Distribution Chapter I, undated (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Note I to 20, undated (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Shepp - Olkin, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Smith - Tong, 1980 Dec. 11 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Sobel-Tonh-Olkin, 1976-1979 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Sobel-Olkin Multinomial Problems in Geometric Probability with Dirichlet Ana, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Sobel-Tong-Olkin, 1979-1981 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Simiu, Hendrickson, Nolan, O, Speigelman "Multivariate Distributions of Direction, 1985 Jan. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Olkin/Simiu Modeling of Joint Extreme Value..., undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Simiu - Olkin Modeling of Joint Extreme Value Distrib..., 1985 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Tomsy - Olkin, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Shafer/Olkin "Adjusting P-Values to Account for..., 1981-1983 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Saunders-Olkin, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - An Elementary Proof of Schur's Majorization Theorem, 1986 Jan. 16 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Searls/Olkin Statistical Aspects...of Sci. Edu. U.S., 1985 Oct. 29 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Tomsy-Olkin, 1965, 1969, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Spiegelman, Simiu, Olkin - "An Adaptive Approach to Nonparametric..., 1985 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Spiegelman/Olkin Semi-Parametric Approach to Nonparametric, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Spiegelman and Olkin - Data Modeling: Detecting Slippage and Contamination, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Sobel-Olkin A Model for Interlaboratory Differences, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Hedges-Olkin, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Hedges-Olkin, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Hedges-Olkin, 1979-1983 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Hedges-Olkin, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Hedges/Olkin "Statistical Inference for Measures of Change and the Overlap Hypothesis", 1983-1985 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Olkin-Hedges Meta-Analysis Book, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Hedges-Olkin Statistical Inference for the Overlap..., 1984-1986 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Hedges/Olkin "Statistical Inference for the Overlap..., 1983-1985 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - The Distance between Two Random Vectors w/Given Dispersion, 1980-1982 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Pukelsheim/Olkin "Distance between Two random Vectors..., 1980-1982 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Saunders-Olkin, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Moore/Olkin Academic Statistics: Growth, Change..., 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Moore/Olkin Statistics: Change and Resources in a, 1981-1983 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Moodie, 1986 July 8-11 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Petkau, Ziked-Olkin, 1918-1980 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Petkau, Zidek - Olkin, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Perlman-Olkin, 1976-1979 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Perlman-Olkin, 1978-1982 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Multivariate Problems, 1957-1958 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Multivariate Problems, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Econ 181C -- Mult Anal. Problems, 1960 Spring (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Prelim Problems, 1947-1961 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Operation Research Problems, 1957-1958 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Binder of Notes, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Satten Glen-Allen, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - NSF Reports (IO), 1994-1998 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - NSA Report (IO), 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Olkin NSF Renewal (Multi-Dimensional...), 1995 Nov. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - NSF Contract, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Proposal Evaluation Form, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Review of DMS-9404200, 1994 Feb. 8 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Class List for Meta-Analysis Course for Winter Quarter 2013, Winter 2013 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - A Statistics Celebration, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Letter to Bernie, 2002 April 9 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Letter from Richard D. Gelber, 2009 Dec. 3 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Notice of New Award, 1991 Sept. 18 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - National Security Agency Proposal for Research Grant in Models and Structures of Multivariate Distributions (2 copies), 1988 March 20 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Sample Surveys - STAT 332, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Markov Cains - Notes - I. Olkin, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Math 253/259 Lecture Notes - S. Karlin, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Probability - Robbins, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Least Squares, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Stochastic Processes - Loeve, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Math 253/259 Lecture Notes - S. Karlin, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Lecture Notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Real Variate Notes - Sroot, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Complex - Sroot, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Sequential Analysis Notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - "On the Factorization of Matrices", undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Not labeled - notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Not labeled - notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - The Jacobians of Certain Matrix Transformations Useful in Multivariable Analysis, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Math 37 - Theory of Functions of Real Variables, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Proposal for Research Project in Multidimensional Statistical Analysis, 1962 Sep 1 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Proposal for Research Project in Mutli-Variate Models in Reliability Theory, 1967 Sep 30 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - [Loose papers] Miscellaneous Notes, 1965-1967 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - NSF Proposal, 1995 October 13 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - [Loose papers] Miscellaneous Notes and Correspondence, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Annals of Internal Medicine, 2008 May 20 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Cross-Disciplinary Research in the Statistical Sciences, 1988 Sep (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - NSA Proposal, 1992 Sep 4 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Multivariate - I, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Chebyshev Bounds for Risks and Error Probabilities in Some Classification Problems, 1969 Jan (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Some Inequalities for Starshaped and Convex Functions, 1967 Aug (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - A Multivariate Exponential Distribution, 1966 Mar (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Estimating the Tails of a Distribution of Known Form, 1978 Dec (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Olkin, 0 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Proposal for Research Project in Mulit-Dimensional Statistical Analysis, 1970 Jan 1-1972 Dec 31 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - NSF, 10/23/1995 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Proposal for Research Project in Multi-Dimensional Statistical Analysis, undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Proposal for Support Under United States-Japan Cooperative Science in Multivariate Statistical Analysis, 1983 Apr 1-1983 June 30 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - NSF Final Report, 1994 Mar 18 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - [Loose papers] Notes, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Dirichlet Integral, 0 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Norms and Condition Numbers, 1964 Feb (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Talks, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Gleser-Olkin New, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Olkin-Rubin Orthogonal Invariance, undated (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Multi volume ineq., undated (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - On Distribution Problems in Multivariate Analysis, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Design/Multivariate - Walker, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Number Theory Notes - Brauer, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Least Square Aspects of Analysis of Variance - R. C. Bose, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Nonparametric/estimation tests - Bahadur, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Student notes multivariate course, 1962 Jan (Box 8, Folder 6)